Leana Copeland

Q Canberra, Australia

☐ leana.copeland@gmail.com

☐ leanacopeland.com

in linkedin.com/in/leana-copeland

github.com/leanaco

I am a user experience researcher with a PhD in computer science. I specialise in quantitative user research, machine learning, and statistical analysis. I have extensive experience with eye tracking, experimental design, and programming. I can apply research methods to a given task, including designing and running controlled laboratory experiments, as well as remote unmoderated and moderated usability testing.

SKILLS

Research

Remote usability testing tools
UserZoom, Optimal Workshop,
Loop11, and Qualtrics

Eye Tracking

Seeing Machines FaceLab 5, EyeWorks, EyeTribe

User experience research methods

Eye tracking studies, moderated usability testing, contextual interviews, remote usability testing, information architecture

Data science

I have experience running statistical analyses with

SPSS, Python, R and Matlab I have experience building machine learning models in

Matlab and Python

Programming

Strong

Python, Matlab, Javascript, HTML, CSS and SQL

Moderate

Java, C, C++, C#, PHP

Communication and team work

I am a strong communicator in both written and verbal form. I work in a collaborative agile team in my current role. We are a multidisciplinary team that works in a 2week sprint.

I bring user experience research capability to the team and work alongside designers, front-end developers, and content writers daily to produce high quality products.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science)

Australian National University

Thesis title: Eye Tracking to Support eLearning

Bachelor of Information Technology (First Class Honours)

July 2012

Australian National University

Thesis title: Extraction of information from Eye Gaze Data.

Bachelor of Science (Double Major Computer Science)

July 2012

Australian National University

EXPERIENCE

UX Researcher Sept 2016 – present

Australian Taxation Office, Canberra Australia

I am part of an agile team who design and conduct a wide range of usability tests. We collect and analyse qualitative and quantitative data, and perform expert reviews.

Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Jan 2016 – Sept 2016

Dec 2016

Australian National University, Canberra Australia

I designed and ran human computer interaction (HCI) experiments, to collect and analyse physiological data. I analysed the data statistically and using machine learning techniques, in particular, artificial neural networks (ANN). I supervised several students and lectured on the topics of HCI and bioinspired computing. I lead a team who designed and developed a web application for HCI outreach activities.

Teaching Assistant

Feb 2013 - June 2016

Australian National University, Canberra Australia

I tutored several courses including a first-year web design and development course, an advanced level course on bio-inspired computing, a human computer interaction course, and an entrepreneurial and innovations course. I also demonstrated in computer laboratories.

Intern 2009

IBM, Canberra Australia

I completed a year-long internship with IBM where I learnt Siebel CRM. I gained experience developing and maintaining Siebel CRM software, and reporting from the system.

AWARDS

- **1. Winner of the Best Paper award** at MHCI 2015: Imperfect Understandings: A Grounded Theory and Eye Gaze Investigation of Human Perceptions of Manipulated and Unmanipulated Digital Images.
- 2. Winner of the Student Design Challenge at OzCHI 2015: VIRK: Virtual work environment to facilitate interaction between the unemployed.